<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Custom Biological Research Feed</title><link>https://mahoon2.github.io/custom_rss_feed/CNSfeed.xml</link><description>Aggregated research articles from Cell, Nature, and Science.</description><language>en-US</language><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Cell: A Bacteroides synthetic biology toolkit to build an in vivo malabsorption biosensor</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01501-6</link><description>Engineered repressible promoters enable tunable fluorescence outputs in Bacteroides and the development of biosensors that report on subclinical gut malabsorption.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01501-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mechanistic insights into RNA chaperoning by Ro60 and La autoantigens</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01479-5</link><description>Structural and functional analyses elucidate the mechanisms by which two ATP-independent RNA chaperones, Ro60 and La, recognize and unfold misfolded RNAs. Diverse noncoding RNAs are associated with this chaperone machine, supporting a wide-ranging role in maintaining RNA homeostasis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01479-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: CRISPR screens in iPSC-derived neurons reveal principles of tau proteostasis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01487-4</link><description>CRISPR screens in iPSC-derived neurons reveal that the E3 ubiquitin ligase CRL5 SOCS4 ubiquitinates tau, that CUL5 expression is correlated with resilience in human Alzheimer’s disease, and that electron transport chain dysfunction alters tau degradation by the proteasome.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01487-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A non-catalytic role for RFC in PCNA-mediated processive DNA synthesis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01478-3</link><description>The RFC clamp loader remains associated with PCNA beyond the loading step, supporting processive DNA replication by stabilizing the inherently unstable PCNA-polymerase ẟ complex.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01478-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Projected impacts of climate change on malaria in Africa</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10015-z</link><description>Projected impacts of climate change on malaria burden in Africa by 2050 highlight the urgent need for climate-resilient malaria control strategies and robust emergency response systems to safeguard progress towards malaria eradication.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10015-z</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Constraints on axion dark matter by distributed intercity quantum sensors</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10034-w</link><description>Amplification and optimal noise filtering in hyperpolarized noble-gas spins of observations from distributed intercity quantum sensors monitoring for unexpected transient rotations of polarized spins set parameter range constraints in the search for axion dark matter.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10034-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Prethermalization by random multipolar driving on a 78-qubit processor</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09977-x</link><description>The existence of a long-lived, prethermal regime in many-body systems with tunable heating rates, driven by structured random protocols, is observed using a 78-qubit superconducting quantum processor.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09977-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Multimodal learning with next-token prediction for large multimodal models</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10041-x</link><description>Emu3 enables large-scale text, image and video learning based solely on next-token prediction, matching the generation and perception performance of task-specific methods, with implications for the development of scalable and unified multimodal intelligence systems.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10041-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Radiation-tolerant atomic-layer-scale RF system for spaceborne communication</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10027-9</link><description>Using a wafer-scale monolayer 2D MoS 2 process instead of conventional silicon-based devices to manufacture components of spaceborne communication systems demonstrates radiation tolerance, low bit error rate and long-term stability, even under much harsher radiation environments.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10027-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Accurate determination of the 3D atomic structure of amorphous materials</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09857-4</link><description>A quantitative framework for atomic electron tomography enables reliable determination of three-dimensional (3D) atomic coordinates and elemental identities in amorphous materials.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09857-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Intestinal macrophages modulate synucleinopathy along the gut–brain axis</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09984-y</link><description>Muscularis macrophages, housekeepers of enteric nervous system integrity and intestinal homeostasis, modulate α-synuclein pathology and neurodegeneration in models of Parkinson’s disease, and understanding the accompanying mechanisms could pave the way for early-stage biomarkers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09984-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Cholinergic modulation of dopamine release drives effortful behaviour</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10046-6</link><description>In the nucleus accumbens, acetylcholine boosts dopamine release to promote effortful behaviour.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10046-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Optical control of integer and fractional Chern insulators</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09777-3</link><description>Optical control of integer and fractional Chern insulators is demonstrated by circularly polarized optical pumping in tMoTe 2 .</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09777-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Environmentally driven immune imprinting protects against allergy</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10001-5</link><description>In a mouse model, environmental immunostimulation in early life led to cross-reactive adaptive immune memory and reduced type II immune responses to allergens, indicating a mechanistic relationship between environmental antigen exposure and subsequent allergy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10001-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Population-scale sequencing resolves determinants of persistent EBV DNA</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10020-2</link><description>Population-scale WGS reveals genetic determinants of persistent EBV DNA, linking immune regulation—especially antigen processing and MHC class II variation—to EBV persistence and heterogeneous disease associations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10020-2</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Pesticide residues alter taxonomic and functional biodiversity in soils</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09991-z</link><description>A wide survey of pesticide effects on soil biodiversity across 373 sites in Europe reveals that pesticide residues occur in 70% of sites and have major effects on soil biodiversity and functional ecology.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09991-z</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Lasing of a cavity-based X-ray source</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10025-x</link><description>Lasing with multi-pass gain is achieved in a diamond-based X-ray cavity at the European XFEL, opening a path to next-generation X-ray science.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10025-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Bandwidth-tuned Mott transition and superconductivity in moiré WSe 2</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10049-3</link><description>Tunable moiré WSe 2 bilayers realize Hubbard-model physics, exhibiting antiferromagnetism, strange metals and superconducting domes, offering a controllable platform to study high-transition-temperature superconductivity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10049-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Human and bacterial genetic variation shape oral microbiomes and health</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10037-7</link><description>Human genetic loci that associate with composition of the oral microbiome are identified using saliva-derived DNA, where the same host genetics also shapes oral health and genetic variation in oral bacteria.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10037-7</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Frequency reproducibility of solid-state thorium-229 nuclear clocks</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09999-5</link><description>The nuclear clock transition of 229m Th in 229 Th:CaF 2 crystals is characterized as a function of doping concentration, temperature and time, demonstrating high reproducibility and identifying ideal operating characteristics of these crystals as nuclear clocks.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09999-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: PAF15–PCNA exhaustion governs the strand-specific control of DNA replication</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10011-3</link><description>PCNA–PAF15 has a key role in determining replisome dynamics during genome replication and protecting against genome instability.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10011-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: A Cambrian soft-bodied biota after the first Phanerozoic mass extinction</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10030-0</link><description>The Huayuan biota exhibits extraordinary biodiversity, illuminating the impact of the Phanerozoic mass extinction around 513 million years ago and offering critical insights into the transformation of global ecosystems in the early Cambrian.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10030-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: An X-ray-emitting protocluster at z ≈ 5.7 reveals rapid structure growth</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09973-1</link><description>Discovery of a protocluster at z = 5.68, merely one billion years after the Big Bang, suggests that large-scale structure must have formed more rapidly in some regions of the early universe than previously thought.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09973-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Low-power integrated optical amplification through second-harmonic resonance</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09959-z</link><description>An integrated optical parametric amplifier on thin-film lithium niobate achieves more than 17 dB gain with less than 200 mW input power.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09959-z</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Field-effect-informed urine liquid biopsy for bladder cancer</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01503-X</link><description>By removing the noise from mutations in tumor-adjacent normal tissue, the field-effect-informed liquid biopsy approach increases the specificity in minimal residual disease detection in patients with non-muscle-invasive bladder cancer and identifies predictive molecular biomarkers specific to different treatment modalities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01503-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A triple-node heart-brain neuroimmune loop underlying myocardial infarction</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01506-5</link><description>This study explores the dissection of a neuroimmune pathway involving the sensory vagus nerve, the hypothalamic paraventricular nucleus, and the sympathetic superior cervical ganglia underlying myocardial infarction.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01506-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: An uORF-encoded mobile peptide sparks systemic stomatal immunity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01437-0</link><description>In Arabidopsis , the uORF-encoded long-distance mobile peptide USIC in pathogen-infected local leaves activates systemic stomatal immunity, leading to stomatal closure in uninfected distal leaves.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01437-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A GPCR-G protein-β-arrestin megacomplex enabled by a versatile allosteric modulator</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01436-9</link><description>Identification of atazanavir as a pan-positive allosteric modulator for family A GPCRs that stabilizes a unique GPCR-G protein-β-arrestin megacomplex and mediates sustained signaling.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01436-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Metabolically regulated proteasome supramolecular organization in situ</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01485-0</link><description>Structural steps along the assembly of proteasome storage granules—membraneless organelles that form in response to metabolic shifts in yeast—are visualized inside cells by cryo-electron tomography. Inactive 26S proteasomes oligomerize into trimers, which assemble into paracrystalline arrays that serve as reservoirs of fully assembled proteasomes under conditions of low energy, ready for reactivation when glucose is restored.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01485-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: An organ-conformal, kirigami-structured bioelectronic patch for precise intracellular delivery</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01434-5</link><description>Organ-level localized delivery is a long-standing challenge, especially for gene therapy. This study establishes a universal conformality theory that enables POCKET—a kirigami-structured bioelectronic patch—to integrate seamlessly with organs and realize precise intracellular electro-delivery of therapeutics without off-target effects.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01434-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: AAVLINK: A potent DNA-recombination method for large cargo delivery in gene therapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01488-6</link><description>Lin et al. introduce AAVLINK, a robust gene delivery platform that surpasses the traditional packaging limits of adeno-associated viruses (AAVs). This system enables efficient delivery of large therapeutic genes and CRISPR components, offering promising avenues for treating genetic disorders such as Dravet syndrome and Phelan-McDermid syndrome.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01488-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: PIKFYVE inhibition mitigates disease in models of diverse forms of ALS</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(26)00051-6</link><description>(Cell 186 , 786–802.e1–e15; February 16, 2023)</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(26)00051-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Can H5N1 avian influenza in dairy cattle be contained in the US?</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01483-7</link><description>The emergence and sustained spread of H5N1 in US dairy cattle since 2024 have demonstrated that highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) is capable of establishing long-term transmission in livestock. Genomic surveillance has clarified national patterns of spatial diffusion, interspecies transmission, and viral evolution, but critical data gaps remain that impede efforts to track virus movements in real time, identify modes of transmission, and inform control efforts.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01483-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: MYC binding to nascent RNA suppresses innate immune signaling by R-loop-derived RNA-DNA hybrids</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01432-1</link><description>RNA-binding-mediated multimerization of MYC concentrates RNA-degrading factors around double-stranded RNAs and R-loops. This prevents aberrant RNAs from accumulating and leaking into the cytosol. Through RNA binding, MYC suppresses innate immune signaling and promotes tumor growth.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01432-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Cell-type resolved protein atlas of brain lysosomes identifies SLC45A1-associated disease as a lysosomal disorder</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01425-4</link><description>This study describes the cell-type-specific lysosomal proteome across the major brain cell types and identifies SLC45A1 as a neuron-specific lysosomal sugar exporter linked to lysosomal storage disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01425-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Fibroblasts of disparate developmental origins harbor anatomically variant scarring potential</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01427-8</link><description>Compared with fibroblasts from other anatomical locations, neural-crest-derived facial fibroblasts upregulate SLIT2-ROBO2 signaling, a pathway important in neural crest cell biology, to promote wound healing with less fibrosis.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01427-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Peripheral cancer attenuates amyloid pathology in Alzheimer’s disease via cystatin-c activation of TREM2</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01433-3</link><description>Peripheral cancer inhibits amyloid pathology and rescues cognition of Alzheimer’s disease through secretion of cystatin-c (Cyst-C), which binds amyloid oligomers and activates TREM2 in microglia and enables microglia to degrade pre-existing plaques.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01433-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Molecular characterization of Ebola virus glycoprotein V75A substitution in the 2018–2020 epidemic</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01435-7</link><description>An Ebola virus glycoprotein mutant, which emerged early during the 2018–2020 epidemic, enhances viral infectivity through multiple mechanisms and may have contributed to its dominance in the outbreak.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01435-7</guid></item><item><title>Science: Multiparameter estimation with an array of entangled atomic sensors</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt2442</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt2442</guid></item><item><title>Science: Platelet-derived integrin- and tetraspanin-enriched tethers exacerbate severe inflammation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2825</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2825</guid></item><item><title>Science: Myelin is repaired by constitutive differentiation of oligodendrocyte progenitors</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2896</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2896</guid></item><item><title>Science: Endogenous retroviruses synthesize heterologous chimeric RNAs to reinforce human early
                     embryo development</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5257</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5257</guid></item><item><title>Science: A negative feedback loop between TERMINAL FLOWER1 and LEAFY protects inflorescence
                     indeterminacy</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5429</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5429</guid></item><item><title>Science: A 5500-year-old Treponema pallidum genome from Sabana de Bogotá, Colombia</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3020</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3020</guid></item><item><title>Science: 143–million-year seawater osmium isotopic record: Trends, rhythms, and dynamics of
                     volcanism and tectonics</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8301</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8301</guid></item><item><title>Science: Observation of the Einstein–de Haas effect in a Bose–Einstein condensate</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2872</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2872</guid></item><item><title>Science: Pan-family pollen signals control an interspecific stigma barrier across Brassicaceae
                     species</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2347</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2347</guid></item><item><title>Science: Reentry and disintegration dynamics of space debris tracked using seismic data</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz4676</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz4676</guid></item><item><title>Science: Who is using AI to code? Global diffusion and impact of generative AI</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9311</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9311</guid></item><item><title>Science: Observation of one-dimensional, charged domain walls in ferroelectric ZrO 2</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb7280</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb7280</guid></item><item><title>Science: Couple-close: Unified approach to semisaturated cyclic scaffolds</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec5748</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec5748</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Identification of Or5v1/Olfr110 as an oxylipin receptor and anti-obesity target</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01429-1</link><description>Or5v1/Olfr110, a high-affinity odor receptor, detects an oxylipin signal to boost liver fat burning and glucose control, and a synthetic agonist can amplify this metabolic benefit.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01429-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mechanistic insights into fatty acid odor detection mediated by class II olfactory receptors</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01431-X</link><description>Cryo-EM structures reveal how Olfr110, a class II odorant receptor, binds hydrophobic odorants such as unsaturated fatty acid metabolites in a large polar pocket with an unconventional activation mechanism, defining the structural basis of odor recognition and guiding drug targeting.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01431-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structural decoding of reversible covalent linkage of odorants in human olfactory receptor OR6A2</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01430-8</link><description>The human olfactory receptor OR6A2, re-engineered to be functional, demonstrates the mechanism by which it detects aldehydes. Using this approach, Wang, Wu, et al. uncovered a broadly conserved activation switch in class II odorant receptors. This work also outlines a practical approach to decode smell, with potential uses in fragrance design and inflammation therapy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01430-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nanoparticles hijack calvarial immune cells for CNS drug delivery and stroke therapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01421-7</link><description>Drug-loaded albumin NPs hijack calvarial immune cells to bypass the BBB via skull-meninges microchannels for CNS drug delivery and stroke therapy, establishing skull-based delivery and immune-assisted transport as a clinically translatable strategy for neurological therapeutics.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01421-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Continuum architecture dynamics of vesicle tethering in exocytosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01374-1</link><description>Data from complementary imaging techniques were integrated into a model that resolves the dynamic exocyst ensemble and membrane architecture during exocytosis, an essential cellular pathway. Sec18 mediates the rate of exocytosis by disassembling the exocyst higher-order structure after vesicle fusion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01374-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Human genetics guides the discovery of CARD9 inhibitors with anti-inflammatory activity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01426-6</link><description>A binder-first approach enables the identification of a druggable pocket and compound for the immune protein CARD9 that dampens its inflammatory signaling. This compound reduces cytokine production in immune cells and in a mouse model, demonstrating how therapeutic modulation can mimic effects of a CARD9 variant protective against Crohn’s disease.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01426-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Multimodal supramolecular targeting chimeras enable spatiotemporally resolved protein degradation in vivo</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01420-5</link><description>Supramolecular targeting chimeras (SupTACs) are a modular and programmable platform that enables tissue-specific and temporally controlled protein degradation in vivo across multiple animal species. SupTAC-mediated ACSL4 degradation effectively alleviates ferroptosis and pulmonary inflammation in a murine model of acute lung injury.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01420-5</guid></item><item><title>Science: A sudden change and recovery in the magnetic environment around a repeating fast radio
                     burst</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq3225</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq3225</guid></item><item><title>Science: Nucleotide metabolic rewiring enables NLRP3 inflammasome hyperactivation in obesity</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9006</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9006</guid></item><item><title>Science: Macrophage MR1 antigen presentation promotes MAIT cell immunity and lung microbiota
                     modulation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr6322</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr6322</guid></item><item><title>Science: Paleogeography modulates marine extinction risk throughout the Phanerozoic</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2627</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2627</guid></item><item><title>Science: Subventricular zone radial glial cells maintain inhibitory neuron production in the
                     human brain</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1803</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1803</guid></item><item><title>Science: A hierarchical shell locks and stabilizes perovskite nanocrystals with near-unity
                     quantum yield</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady1370</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady1370</guid></item><item><title>Science: Complex mesoscale landscapes beneath Antarctica mapped from space</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2532</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2532</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of the lysosomal KICSTOR-GATOR1-SAMTOR nutrient-sensing supercomplex</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</link><description>This study reveals how KICSTOR and GATOR1 assemble into a crescent-shaped lysosomal complex that regulates mTORC1 during amino acid starvation and how SAMTOR binds KICSTOR in an S-adenosylmethionine-incompatible conformation to couple methionine sensing to mTORC1 regulation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: EcDNA-borne structural variants drive oncogenic fusion transcript amplification</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</link><description>Extrachromosomal DNA (ecDNA) is a major source of oncogenic fusions across cancer types, generating tissue-specific fusion landscapes with diagnostic potential. EcDNA-borne PVT1 5′-end fusions stabilize partner RNAs and boost oncogene output.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: In vivo detection of immune responses via cytokine activity labeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</link><description>Cytokine receptor dimerization, induced by the binding of cytokines, can be converted into a genetically traceable fluorescent signal and engineered into reporter mouse lines to visualize processes in vivo . An interleukin-17A reporter mouse line clarifies the location of IL-17A responsive cells in the ileum, while an interferon-γ line can highlight relevant effector populations of T cells in tumors.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Extracellular GPX4 impairs antitumor immunity via dendritic ZP3 receptors</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</link><description>GPX4 released by ferroptotic cancer cells suppresses dendritic cell maturation and T cell priming by binding to ZP3. Blocking the GPX4-ZP3 interaction restores dendritic activity, boosts cytotoxic T cells, and enhances chemo-, radio-, and immunotherapy efficacy in preclinical cancer models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A glycolytic shunt via the pentose phosphate pathway is a metabolic checkpoint for nervous system sensory homeostasis and axonal regeneration</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</link><description>The pentose phosphate pathway plays a dual role in enabling homeostatic and regenerative adaptations to environmental stimuli and injuries and can be leveraged to promote regeneration and recovery after spinal cord injury.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of pancreatic hIAPP fibrils derived from patients with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</link><description>Cryo-EM structures of hIAPP fibrils extracted from the surgically excised pancreases of patients with type 2 diabetes revealed a distinct fold with unique ligand binding compared to those prepared in vitro .</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: FOCAS: Transcriptome-wide screening of individual m 6 A sites functionally dissects epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</link><description>We developed FOCAS as a CRISPR-based platform enabling precise, high-throughput dissection of individual m 6 A sites across mRNA and carRNAs. It reveals RNA element-dependent m 6 A functions within genes, illuminating the context-dependent epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Neuronal calcium spikes enable vector inversion in the Drosophila brain</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</link><description>In the fly central complex, PFNa neurons switch from firing classical sodium spikes when depolarized to firing non-canonical T-type calcium spikes when hyperpolarized. This bidirectional spiking allows the PFNa population to signal both a standard two-dimensional vector and its inverse.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mapping cellular targets of covalent cancer drugs in the entire mammalian body</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</link><description>vCATCH is a volumetric tissue labeling technique enabling cellular-resolution mapping of covalent drug targets throughout the entire mammalian body.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nuclear speckle proteins form intrinsic and MALAT1 -dependent microphases</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</link><description>In nuclear speckles, sequence-encoded inter-domain attractive and repulsive interactions drive proteins to form hierarchical structures, including size-limited microphases, clusters of microphases, micron-scale double emulsions in protein mixtures, and microphases stabilized by preferential and protein-specific binding to the lncRNA MALAT1 .</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Targeting TFAP2β condensation suppresses the development of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</link><description>TFAP2β condensation suppresses esophageal squamous cell carcinoma progression by repressing ZNF131 transcription and recruiting other key regulators; the small molecule A6 enhances TFAP2β condensation and inhibits ESCC growth in cells, organoids, and mice, highlighting a potential therapeutic approach for ESCC.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Sensitized mast cells for targeted drug delivery and augmented cancer immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</link><description>IgE-sensitized mast cells loaded with anticancer drugs target antigen-positive tumors, releasing therapeutics as well as chemokines and cytokines for enhanced lymphocyte infiltration and improved local immunity, demonstrating potential for personalized cancer therapy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</guid></item></channel></rss>