<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Custom Biological Research Feed</title><link>https://mahoon2.github.io/custom_rss_feed/CNSfeed.xml</link><description>Aggregated research articles from Cell, Nature, and Science.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:26:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Science: Mechanosensitive genomic enhancers potentiate the cellular response to matrix stiffness</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adl1988</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adl1988</guid></item><item><title>Science: Cortical glutamatergic and GABAergic inputs support learning-driven hippocampal stability</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adn0623</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adn0623</guid></item><item><title>Science: Chromothripsis and ecDNA initiated by N4BP2 nuclease fragmentation of cytoplasm-exposed
                     chromosomes</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ado0977</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ado0977</guid></item><item><title>Science: Locating the missing chlorophylls f in far-red photosystem I</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ado6830</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ado6830</guid></item><item><title>Science: Hepatic leukemia factor directs tissue residency of proinflammatory memory CD4 + T cells</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adp0714</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adp0714</guid></item><item><title>Science: Spatial and morphological organization of mitochondria in neurons across a connectome</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads6674</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads6674</guid></item><item><title>Science: Shapiro steps in strongly-interacting Fermi gases</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads8885</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads8885</guid></item><item><title>Science: Observation of Shapiro steps in an ultracold atomic Josephson junction</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads9061</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads9061</guid></item><item><title>Science: ARF3-mediated auxin signaling is essential for sex determination in cucumber</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2006</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2006</guid></item><item><title>Science: Global energy sector methane emissions estimated by using facility-level satellite
                     observations</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv3183</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv3183</guid></item><item><title>Science: Multispecies pangenomes reveal a pervasive influence of population size on structural
                     variation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1931</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1931</guid></item><item><title>Science: Comparative analysis of human and mouse ovaries across age</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx0659</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx0659</guid></item><item><title>Science: Mesoporous optically clear heat insulators for sustainable building envelopes</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5568</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5568</guid></item><item><title>Science: Substantial water retained early in Earth’s deep mantle</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5883</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5883</guid></item><item><title>Science: Progressive eastward rupture of the Main Marmara fault toward Istanbul</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz0072</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz0072</guid></item><item><title>Science: Infrared radiation is an ancient pollination signal</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz1728</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz1728</guid></item><item><title>Science: Three-component assembly and structure-function relationships of (–)-gukulenin A</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea9310</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea9310</guid></item><item><title>Science: Structure and organization of AMPA receptor-TARP complexes in the mammalian cerebellum</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb3577</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb3577</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Fasting boosts breast cancer therapy efficacy via glucocorticoid activation</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09869-0</link><description>Beneficial effects of fasting combined with endocrine therapy for oestrogen receptor-α-expressing breast cancers can be recapitulated using exogenous glucocorticoid receptor ligands instead of fasting to reduce harmful effects.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09869-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Quantifying grain boundary deformation mechanisms in small-grained metals</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09800-7</link><description>Experimental observations in small-grained polycrystals suggest a new concept of considering metallic grain boundaries not as defects but as separate defect-containing lattices, providing a potential explanation for the deformation behaviour of nanocrystalline metals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09800-7</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Gene-drive-capable mosquitoes suppress patient-derived malaria in Tanzania</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09685-6</link><description>Engineering of local Anopheles gambiae under containment enables the generation of a transgenic strain equipped with non-autonomous gene drive capabilities that robustly inhibits genetically diverse Plasmodium falciparum isolates obtained from naturally infected children.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09685-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Erythropoietin receptor on cDC1s dictates immune tolerance</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09824-z</link><description>The tolerogenic activity of type 1 conventional dendritic cells (cDC1s) is determined by EPOR, which is preferentially expressed in cDC1s and induces antigen-specific FOXP3-expressing regulatory T cells.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09824-z</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Human gut M cells resemble dendritic cells and present gluten antigen</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09829-8</link><description>An intestinal organoid model recapitulates human microfold (M) cell function and transcriptomic profiling and biochemical assays demonstrate that M cells uptake and present antigens to the immune system via the class II major histocompatibility complex.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09829-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Cross-regulation of [2Fe–2S] cluster synthesis by ferredoxin-2 and frataxin</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09822-1</link><description>A finely balanced ratio of ferredoxin-2 (FDX2) and frataxin (FXN) is essential for the synthesis of iron–sulfur clusters, and interventions targeting this ratio could provide a way to treat related diseases, such as Friedreich’s ataxia.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09822-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Sterilization and contraception increase lifespan across vertebrates</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09836-9</link><description>Data collected from zoos and aquariums worldwide show that hormonal contraception or permanent surgical sterilization in mammals increase life expectancy, with different mechanisms in males and females.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09836-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Earliest evidence of making fire</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09855-6</link><description>Baked sediment, heat-shattered artefacts and introduced pyrite in a 400,000-year-old Palaeolithic occupation site in Suffolk, UK provide evidence of intentional fire-making, marking a pivotal moment in human development.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09855-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Observation of deuteron and antideuteron formation from resonance-decay nucleons</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09775-5</link><description>The ALICE Collaboration provides details on the microscopic mechanism that ends up creating antideuteron in high-energy proton–proton collisions at the Large Hadron Collider.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09775-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Hot droughts in the Amazon provide a window to a future hypertropical climate</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09728-y</link><description>Thirty years of forest demographic data, combined with recent ecophysiological measurements, reveal that intense Amazon droughts sharply increase tree mortality once soil moisture falls below a threshold, and that these hot droughts will become more frequent and intense as Earth warms towards hypertropical conditions.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09728-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: A direct role for a mitochondrial targeting sequence in signalling stress</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09834-x</link><description>Cells can sense mitochondrial damage through signalling via an unimported mitochondrial targeting sequence.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09834-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Neutrophils preserve energy storage in sympathetically activated adipocytes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09839-6</link><description>Neutrophil-derived IL-1β has a role in preserving lipid stores during metabolic stress.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09839-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Mapping the genetic landscape across 14 psychiatric disorders</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09820-3</link><description>Genomic analyses applied to 14 childhood- and adult-onset psychiatric disorders identifies five underlying genomic factors that explain the majority of the genetic variance of the individual disorders.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09820-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: An RNA splicing system that excises DNA transposons from animal mRNAs</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09853-8</link><description>A new type of mRNA splicing mechanism discovered in Caenorhabditis elegans that detects and removes inverted repeats also occurs in human cells, thereby providing another strategy to protect against the negative effects of transposable elements.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09853-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Uncovering the role of LINE-1 in the evolution of lung adenocarcinoma</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09825-y</link><description>Lung adenocarcinomas bearing the ID2 mutational signature display increased LINE-1 retrotransposon activity, which contributes to their fast evolutionary dynamics and aggressive phenotype.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09825-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Somatic evolution following cancer treatment in normal tissue</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09792-4</link><description>High-depth sequencing of non-cancerous tissue from patients with metastatic cancer reveals single-base mutational signatures of alcohol, smoking and cancer treatments, and reveals how exogenous factors, including cancer therapies, affect somatic cell evolution.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09792-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Protected area management has significant spillover effects on vegetation</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09837-8</link><description>Analysis of effect sizes of vegetation spillovers from protected areas in Australia shows that 71% of over 3,063 analysed protected areas had a positive spillover effect, and that these effects covary with protected area management type.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09837-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Laser-based conversion electron Mössbauer spectroscopy of 229 ThO 2</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09776-4</link><description>Laser-induced conversion electron Mössbauer spectroscopy, which detects electrons emitted by 229 Th nuclei in a thin ThO 2 sample excited by vacuum ultraviolet light, is demonstrated, opening the possibility of a conversion-electron-based nuclear clock.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09776-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Agonists for cytosolic bacterial receptor ALPK1 induce antitumour immunity</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09828-9</link><description>The ALPK1 agonist UDSP-Hep stimulates tumour-cell antigen presentation, macrophage–DC cross-priming and differentiation of protective memory T cells.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09828-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Causal modelling of gene effects from regulators to programs to traits</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09866-3</link><description>Approaches combining genetic association and Perturb-seq data that link genetic variants to functional programs to traits are described.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09866-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Multimodal AI generates virtual population for tumor microenvironment modeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</link><description>GigaTIME leverages multimodal AI to generate virtual multiplex immunofluorescence (mIF) profiles from standard H&amp;E slides, enabling comprehensive tumor immune microenvironment modeling across a large (&gt;14,000) and diverse patient population. This virtual approach unlocks new opportunities for large-scale clinical discoveries that were previously hindered by the scarcity of mIF data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Sensitized mast cells for targeted drug delivery and augmented cancer immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</link><description>IgE-sensitized mast cells loaded with anticancer drugs target antigen-positive tumors, releasing therapeutics as well as chemokines and cytokines for enhanced lymphocyte infiltration and improved local immunity, demonstrating potential for personalized cancer therapy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Biomaterial-minimalistic photoactivated bioprinting of cell-dense tissues</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01308-X</link><description>We developed a bioprinting strategy that turns living cells into cell-only bioinks, enabling light-based 3D bioprinting of tissues at native, ultrahigh cell densities (up to ∼10 9 cells mL −1 ) to rapidly yield functional neural circuit and beating mini-heart models as well as vascularized liver and skin grafts that promote regeneration.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01308-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structural basis of microtubule-mediated signal transduction</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</link><description>This study presents a structural basis for understanding how microtubules can act as spatiotemporal signal sensors to control cellular responses.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Psilocybin triggers an activity-dependent rewiring of large-scale cortical networks</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</link><description>Psilocybin reshapes brain networks through activity-dependent plasticity, including a weakening of recurrent cortical loops that could underlie its therapeutic effects.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A fin-loop-like structure in GPX4 underlies neuroprotection from ferroptosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01310-8</link><description>A fin-like structural loop in GPX4 is critical for anchoring the enzyme to cellular membranes, thereby preventing ferroptosis. A patient-associated R152H mutation destabilizes this loop, leading to ferroptotic neurodegeneration in human cells and mouse models and revealing Alzheimer’s-like molecular signatures. These findings position ferroptosis as a critical driver (and potential therapeutic target) of neurodegenerative disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01310-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Renal PIEZO2 is an essential regulator of renin</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01309-1</link><description>The force-sensing ion channel PIEZO2 is an essential regulator of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS), a pathway that controls blood volume. Loss of PIEZO2 in the kidney cells that produce renin disrupts cellular calcium dynamics and levels of the enzyme in mice, linking mechanotransduction in the kidney to the RAAS.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01309-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Autoantibody-triggered podocyte membrane budding drives autoimmune kidney disease</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01306-6</link><description>Kidney podocytes of the blood-urine filter form autoimmunoglobulin-triggered extracellular vesicles (AIT-EVs) for intra- and extracellular waste removal into the urine, a cellular reaction that links basal immune complex clearance to podocyte injury and allows non-invasive diagnosis and monitoring of kidney autoimmune activity.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01306-6</guid></item><item><title>Science: Pre- and postantibiotic epoch: The historical spread of antimicrobial resistance</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr1522</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr1522</guid></item><item><title>Science: Semiseparated biphasic bicontinuous dielectric elastomer for high-performance artificial
                     muscle</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr3521</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr3521</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Fertilization triggers early proteomic symmetry breaking in mammalian embryos</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01255-3</link><description>Single-cell proteomics finds asymmetries between sister blastomeres from the 2-cell stage in human and mouse embryos, defining two states: alpha and beta. Alpha-beta asymmetry can be traced back to the zygote, is triggered by fertilization, and is linked to differential developmental potential, with beta blastomeres having a higher potential.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01255-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Retraction notice to: Transcriptome-scale RNA-targeting CRISPR screens reveal essential lncRNAs in human cells</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01367-4</link><description>(Cell 187 , 7637–7654.e1–e29; December 26, 2024)</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01367-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: pTα enhances mRNA translation and potentiates CAR T cells for solid tumor eradication</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</link><description>Addition of a pre-TCR domain to chimeric antigen receptors boosts mRNA translation and enables durable tumor control by T cells in both blood and solid cancers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Membrane potential mediates the cellular response to mechanical pressure</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01253-X</link><description>Cells in tissues need to know when to start growing and when to stop growing to quickly heal wounds but prevent tumorous overgrowth. Membrane potential allows cells to sense physical forces, including those from neighboring cells, and thereby regulates growth.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01253-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A stepwise decoding mechanism for heat sensing in plants connects lipid remodeling to a nuclear signaling cascade</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01252-8</link><description>A complete hierarchical thermo-decoding mechanism in plants connects cell membrane lipid remodeling during heat stress to the downstream signaling cascade in the nucleus. Field trials demonstrate the potential application of this mechanism in customized heat-tolerant crop design in rice.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01252-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: The unique architecture of umbrella toxins permits a two-tiered molecular bet-hedging strategy for interbacterial antagonism</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</link><description>Umbrella toxin particles produced by Actinobacteria contain five spokes tipped with variable lectin domains. Here, Zhao et al. show that these lectins mediate species-specific binding to a previously unrecognized cell surface carbohydrate polymer and propose that the modular nature of umbrella particles enables bet hedging against unpredictable competitor encounters.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: An archaeal transcription factor bridges prokaryotic and eukaryotic regulatory paradigms</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01241-3</link><description>Methanogenic archaea use the one-component system AmzR to sense methylamines and regulate the expression of methylamine-metabolizing genes. Unlike other prokaryotic one-component systems, the DNA-binding motif of AmzR resembles a structural fold typically found in eukaryotic transcription factors. This discovery narrows the gap between prokaryotic and eukaryotic regulatory proteins.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01241-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Thermodynamic principles link in vitro transcription factor affinities to single-molecule chromatin states in cells</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01300-5</link><description>In vitro -derived insights into features that drive transcription factor binding to DNA, including motif-adjacent sequence, enable prediction of chromatin states and transcription factor occupancy in cells.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01300-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Stress-induced sympathetic hyperactivation drives hair follicle necrosis to trigger autoimmunity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01247-4</link><description>Acute stress causes immediate hair follicle necrosis and hair loss via sympathetic nerves, which in turn activates and expands autoreactive CD8⁺ T cells targeting hair follicles. Thus, a single stress event not only causes immediate tissue damage but also predisposes the tissue to future autoimmune attack.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01247-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Properties and functions of transcriptionally distinct enteric neurons</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01246-2</link><description>Developing genetic access to transcriptionally distinct enteric neurons in vivo enables the examination of morphological heterogeneity across cell types as well as cell-type-specific influences on GI function.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01246-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: IL-1R1-positive dorsal raphe neurons drive self-imposed social withdrawal in sickness</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01245-0</link><description>During sickness, animals exhibit prolonged social withdrawal, a response that may limit disease spread. Elevated IL-1β levels during inflammation activate IL-1R1-expressing neurons in the dorsal raphe nucleus to drive self-imposed withdrawal, highlighting a neural mechanism through which immune activation reconfigures social behavior.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01245-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: RNA innate immunity constitutes a barrier for interspecies chimerism</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01244-9</link><description>Interspecies PSC co-culture induces horizontal RNA transfer that activates innate immunity in “winner” mouse cells, a response that is alleviated by Mavs deletion, thereby enhancing “loser” human PSC survival and chimerism.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01244-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Inhibition of oligomeric BAX by an anti-apoptotic dimer</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01242-5</link><description>A full-length dimeric form of the anti-apoptotic protein BCL-w can block oligomeric BAX-driven mitochondrial permeabilization and apoptosis, revealing a new layer of cell-death control.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01242-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Elucidating pathway-selective biased CCKBR agonism for Alzheimer’s disease treatment</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</link><description>Clinical evidence from AD patients reveals an association between impaired CCKBR-Gq signaling and disease severity, guiding structure-based design of a Gq-biased agonist that rescues memory and pathology in AD animal models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Inhibition of heme biosynthesis triggers cuproptosis in acute myeloid leukemia</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01233-4</link><description>Reduced levels of the essential metabolite heme are a common feature of acute myeloid leukemia, and consequently, leukemic cells are highly sensitive to inhibition of de novo heme synthesis. Blockade of heme biosynthesis enzymes triggers cuproptosis, a form of copper-dependent cell death that is molecularly distinct from other cell death pathways.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01233-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: BRAIN-MAGNET: A functional genomics atlas for interpretation of non-coding variants</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</link><description>BRAIN-MAGNET, a convolutional neural network trained on 148,198 functionally tested non-coding regulatory elements, predicts enhancer activity directly from DNA sequence and identifies nucleotides essential for function. This functional genomic atlas and BRAIN-MAGNET prioritize disease-relevant non-coding variants, advancing functional interpretation of the regulatory genome in neurodevelopment and neurological disease.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Ancient RNA expression profiles from the extinct woolly mammoth</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01231-0</link><description>Ancient RNA profiles from Late Pleistocene woolly mammoths were sequenced from permafrost-preserved mummified tissues, revealing tissue-specific transcriptional functions and gene expression regulatory dynamics. These findings highlight the potential of ancient RNA molecules to provide additional biological information, thus advancing toward integrative paleogenetic research beyond the limits of DNA sequencing alone.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01231-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Single-cell susceptibility to viral infection is driven by variable cell states</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01193-6</link><description>Not all cells that can be infected by a virus become infected with that virus. Single-cell clone tracing reveals intrinsic cell states with variable expression patterns that increase susceptibility to viral infection, and this applies for several distinct viruses.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01193-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Molecular grammars of predicted intrinsically disordered regions that span the human proteome</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01191-2</link><description>Grammars inferred using NARDINI+ (GIN) is a resource that uncovers molecular grammars of intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs) across the human proteome, revealing how distinct grammars underlie protein localization, function, and disease associations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01191-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Phase separation to buffer growth-mediated dilution in synthetic circuits</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01182-1</link><description>Phase separation stabilizes synthetic gene circuits and boosts production under dynamic growth conditions. By locally concentrating transcription factors at promoters, it protects gene expression from growth-driven dilution and provides a broadly applicable strategy for gene circuit engineering.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01182-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Genome sequences of extant and extinct gibbons reveal their phylogeny, demographic history, and conservation status</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01181-X</link><description>This study presents a comprehensive evolutionary history of gibbons by resolving their contentious phylogeny, reclassifying an extinct species with ancient DNA, and identifying a structural variant potentially contributing to their limb elongation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01181-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: StealTHY: An immunogen-free CRISPR platform to expose concealed metastasis regulators in immunocompetent models</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01136-5</link><description>By sidestepping Cas9 immunogenicity, the StealTHY CRISPR platform enables immune-compatible in vivo genetic screens, directly translatable to humanized cancer models. Using this immune-stealth strategy allows for the discovery of metastatic drivers and reveals the AMH-AMHR2 axis as a clinically actionable pathway for dampening carcinoma metastasis.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01136-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Gut-to-brain signaling restricts dietary protein intake during recovery from catabolic states</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01134-1</link><description>Gut sensing of dietary amino-acid-derived ammoniagenesis restricts dietary protein intake during recovery from catabolic states.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01134-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Zebrafish use spectral information to suppress the visual background</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01138-9</link><description>Vertebrate eyes first evolved in water, where spectral content rapidly fades with distance. Zebrafish exploit this loss by antagonizing cone signals to suppress the background, pointing to distance estimation—rather than color—as an ancestral cone function.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01138-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Charting the landscape of cytoskeletal diversity in microbial eukaryotes</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01127-4</link><description>An imaging resource of over 200 microbial eukaryotic species provides a glimpse into the remarkable universe of cytoskeletal diversity.</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01127-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Bacterial tubular networks channel carbohydrates in insect endosymbiosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01130-4</link><description>Bacteria with an intracellular lifestyle need to feed from inside their host cells. This study shows an adaptation of certain symbiotic bacteria, allowing them to actively retrieve nutrients from the host. High-pressure cryofixation has been combined with volume electron microscopy and in situ high spatial resolution chemical analysis. It reveals a complex bacterial membranous network that increases the exchange interface between the bacteria and host cytosol and maximizes carbohydrate acquisition.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01130-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Adrenergic signaling coordinates distant and local responses to amputation in axolotl</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01125-0</link><description>The nervous system regulates a systemic response following amputation that primes distant appendages for faster regeneration upon a second injury, a scenario relevant to salamanders in the wild who experience repeated limb loss.</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01125-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: De novo designed voltage-gated anion channels suppress neuron firing</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01091-8</link><description>This study reports the successful de novo design of voltage-gated anion channels that are distinct from native channels. They exhibit voltage-dependent ion conductance and are capable of being tuned for biological applications such as neuronal suppression.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01091-8</guid></item></channel></rss>