<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Custom Biological Research Feed</title><link>https://mahoon2.github.io/custom_rss_feed/CNSfeed.xml</link><description>Aggregated research articles from Cell, Nature, and Science.</description><language>en-US</language><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Cell: PIKFYVE inhibition mitigates disease in models of diverse forms of ALS</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(26)00051-6</link><description>(Cell 186 , 786–802.e1–e15; February 16, 2023)</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(26)00051-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Can H5N1 avian influenza in dairy cattle be contained in the US?</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01483-7</link><description>The emergence and sustained spread of H5N1 in US dairy cattle since 2024 have demonstrated that highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) is capable of establishing long-term transmission in livestock. Genomic surveillance has clarified national patterns of spatial diffusion, interspecies transmission, and viral evolution, but critical data gaps remain that impede efforts to track virus movements in real time, identify modes of transmission, and inform control efforts.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01483-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: MYC binding to nascent RNA suppresses innate immune signaling by R-loop-derived RNA-DNA hybrids</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01432-1</link><description>RNA-binding-mediated multimerization of MYC concentrates RNA-degrading factors around double-stranded RNAs and R-loops. This prevents aberrant RNAs from accumulating and leaking into the cytosol. Through RNA binding, MYC suppresses innate immune signaling and promotes tumor growth.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01432-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Cell-type resolved protein atlas of brain lysosomes identifies SLC45A1-associated disease as a lysosomal disorder</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01425-4</link><description>This study describes the cell-type-specific lysosomal proteome across the major brain cell types and identifies SLC45A1 as a neuron-specific lysosomal sugar exporter linked to lysosomal storage disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01425-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Fibroblasts of disparate developmental origins harbor anatomically variant scarring potential</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01427-8</link><description>Compared with fibroblasts from other anatomical locations, neural-crest-derived facial fibroblasts upregulate SLIT2-ROBO2 signaling, a pathway important in neural crest cell biology, to promote wound healing with less fibrosis.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01427-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Peripheral cancer attenuates amyloid pathology in Alzheimer’s disease via cystatin-c activation of TREM2</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01433-3</link><description>Peripheral cancer inhibits amyloid pathology and rescues cognition of Alzheimer’s disease through secretion of cystatin-c (Cyst-C), which binds amyloid oligomers and activates TREM2 in microglia and enables microglia to degrade pre-existing plaques.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01433-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Molecular characterization of Ebola virus glycoprotein V75A substitution in the 2018–2020 epidemic</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01435-7</link><description>An Ebola virus glycoprotein mutant, which emerged early during the 2018–2020 epidemic, enhances viral infectivity through multiple mechanisms and may have contributed to its dominance in the outbreak.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01435-7</guid></item><item><title>Science: Multiparameter estimation with an array of entangled atomic sensors</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt2442</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt2442</guid></item><item><title>Science: Platelet-derived integrin- and tetraspanin-enriched tethers exacerbate severe inflammation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2825</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2825</guid></item><item><title>Science: Myelin is repaired by constitutive differentiation of oligodendrocyte progenitors</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2896</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2896</guid></item><item><title>Science: Endogenous retroviruses synthesize heterologous chimeric RNAs to reinforce human early
                     embryo development</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5257</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5257</guid></item><item><title>Science: A negative feedback loop between TERMINAL FLOWER1 and LEAFY protects inflorescence
                     indeterminacy</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5429</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv5429</guid></item><item><title>Science: A 5500-year-old Treponema pallidum genome from Sabana de Bogotá, Colombia</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3020</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3020</guid></item><item><title>Science: 143–million-year seawater osmium isotopic record: Trends, rhythms, and dynamics of
                     volcanism and tectonics</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8301</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8301</guid></item><item><title>Science: Observation of the Einstein–de Haas effect in a Bose–Einstein condensate</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2872</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2872</guid></item><item><title>Science: Pan-family pollen signals control an interspecific stigma barrier across Brassicaceae
                     species</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2347</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2347</guid></item><item><title>Science: Reentry and disintegration dynamics of space debris tracked using seismic data</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz4676</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz4676</guid></item><item><title>Science: Who is using AI to code? Global diffusion and impact of generative AI</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9311</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9311</guid></item><item><title>Science: Observation of one-dimensional, charged domain walls in ferroelectric ZrO 2</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb7280</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aeb7280</guid></item><item><title>Science: Couple-close: Unified approach to semisaturated cyclic scaffolds</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec5748</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec5748</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Identification of Or5v1/Olfr110 as an oxylipin receptor and anti-obesity target</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01429-1</link><description>Or5v1/Olfr110, a high-affinity odor receptor, detects an oxylipin signal to boost liver fat burning and glucose control, and a synthetic agonist can amplify this metabolic benefit.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01429-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mechanistic insights into fatty acid odor detection mediated by class II olfactory receptors</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01431-X</link><description>Cryo-EM structures reveal how Olfr110, a class II odorant receptor, binds hydrophobic odorants such as unsaturated fatty acid metabolites in a large polar pocket with an unconventional activation mechanism, defining the structural basis of odor recognition and guiding drug targeting.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01431-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structural decoding of reversible covalent linkage of odorants in human olfactory receptor OR6A2</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01430-8</link><description>The human olfactory receptor OR6A2, re-engineered to be functional, demonstrates the mechanism by which it detects aldehydes. Using this approach, Wang, Wu, et al. uncovered a broadly conserved activation switch in class II odorant receptors. This work also outlines a practical approach to decode smell, with potential uses in fragrance design and inflammation therapy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01430-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Afar fossil shows broad distribution and versatility of Paranthropus</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09826-x</link><description>With its attribution to Paranthropus , a 2.6-million-year-old partial mandible expands the range of the genus into the Afar region of Ethiopia and adds to our understanding of hominin evolution in eastern Africa.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09826-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Construction of complex and diverse DNA sequences using DNA three-way junctions</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10006-0</link><description>Sidewinder enables high-fidelity DNA assembly by separating the information that guides assembly from the final assembled sequence.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10006-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Extreme barocaloric effect at dissolution</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10013-1</link><description>An extreme barocaloric effect in NH 4 SCN aqueous solutions is enabled by pressure-induced dissolution and precipitation, but without using a separate heat-transfer liquid.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10013-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Temporal tissue dynamics from a spatial snapshot</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09876-1</link><description>One-shot tissue dynamics reconstruction can infer changes in tissue composition over time, from single-time-point spatial proteomics of human cancers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09876-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Pyramidal neurons proportionately alter cortical interneuron subtypes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09996-8</link><description>Pyramidal neuron-driven mechanisms actively promote the survival and terminal differentiation of their associated interneuron subtypes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09996-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Rock art from at least 67,800 years ago in Sulawesi</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09968-y</link><description>A hand stencil painted on a cave wall on a small island off the coast of Sulawesi more than 67,800 years ago suggests a very early occupation of Wallacea.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09968-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Core–envelope miscibility in sub-Neptunes and super-Earths</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09970-4</link><description>First-principles molecular dynamics driven by density functional theory is used to show that silicate and hydrogen are completely miscible over a wide range of plausible core–envelope pressure–temperature conditions.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09970-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Four camera-type eyes in the earliest vertebrates from the Cambrian Period</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09966-0</link><description>Early vertebrates, particularly myllokunmingids, possessed four camera-type eyes (a pair of lateral eyes and pineal and parapineal organs), which indicates that these structures functioned in image formation, in support of the hypothesis that the four camera-type eyes represent an ancestral vertebrate trait.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09966-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Identification of an allosteric site on the E3 ligase adapter cereblon</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09994-w</link><description>An allosteric site on the E3 ligase adapter cereblon can be targeted to modulate the efficacy of cereblon in targeted protein degradation applications.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09994-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Predatory aggression evolved through adaptations to noradrenergic circuits</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10009-x</link><description>Noradrenergic circuits support and balance aggressive behavioural states in predatory nematodes, distinguish predatory from non-predatory nematode species and are associated with the evolution of complex behavioural traits.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10009-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: The potential for bridgmanite megacrysts to drive magma ocean segregation</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10063-5</link><description>Large-scale molecular dynamics simulations show that the crystal–melt interfacial energies of MgSiO 3 bridgmanite increase substantially with pressure, potentially forming unusually large bridgmanite crystals and suggesting a new physical mechanism driving magma ocean segregation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10063-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Ageing promotes microglial accumulation of slow-degrading synaptic proteins</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09987-9</link><description>Newly developed mouse models that enable cell-specific analyses of proteostasis dynamics across the lifespan of the mice reveal key aspects of neuronal proteostasis with ageing.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09987-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Oxygen-free metabolism in the bird inner retina supported by the pecten</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09978-w</link><description>While the photoreceptor outer segments in the bird outer retina have access to oxygen, the inner retina operates under chronic anoxia, supported by anaerobic glycolysis in the retinal neurons.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09978-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Critical role for a high-plasticity cell state in lung cancer</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09985-x</link><description>The high-plasticity cell state (HPCS) is a critical hub that enables reciprocal transitions between cancer cell states, and targeting the HPCS may suppress cancer progression and eradicate treatment resistance.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09985-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Large-scale dynamos driven by shear-flow-induced jets</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09912-0</link><description>Aadvanced computer simulations of three-dimensional turbulence reveal that the ab initio generation of large-scale magnetic fields is driven by shear-flow-induced jets; an analytical model is derived which reproduces the essential features of the flow- and field-generation mechanisms.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09912-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Common variation in meiosis genes shapes human recombination and aneuploidy</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09964-2</link><description>Analysis of data from pre-implantation genetic testing sheds light on the genetic basis of meiotic-origin aneuploidy, the leading cause of human pregnancy loss, identifying common genetic variants associated with maternal meiotic errors.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09964-2</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Dissecting gene regulatory networks governing human cortical cell fate</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09997-7</link><description>Systematic screening of transcription factors reveals conserved mechanisms governing cortical radial glia lineage progression across primates and provides a framework for functional dissection of gene regulatory networks in human cortical neurogenesis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09997-7</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Quantum spin resonance in engineered proteins for multimodal sensing</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09971-3</link><description>A recently developed class of magneto-sensitive fluorescent proteins are engineered to alter the properties of their response to magnetic fields and radio frequencies, enabling multimodal sensing of biological systems.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09971-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: LetA defines a structurally distinct transporter family</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09990-0</link><description>The distinct architecture of the Escherichia coli membrane transporter LetA mediates lipid trafficking across the bacterial envelope in partnership with the tunnel-like complex LetB.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09990-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Probing quantum mechanics with nanoparticle matter-wave interferometry</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09917-9</link><description>Quantum interference of sodium nanoparticles, which can each contain more than 7,000 atoms at masses greater than 170,000 Da, is demonstrated.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09917-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nanoparticles hijack calvarial immune cells for CNS drug delivery and stroke therapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01421-7</link><description>Drug-loaded albumin NPs hijack calvarial immune cells to bypass the BBB via skull-meninges microchannels for CNS drug delivery and stroke therapy, establishing skull-based delivery and immune-assisted transport as a clinically translatable strategy for neurological therapeutics.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01421-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Continuum architecture dynamics of vesicle tethering in exocytosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01374-1</link><description>Data from complementary imaging techniques were integrated into a model that resolves the dynamic exocyst ensemble and membrane architecture during exocytosis, an essential cellular pathway. Sec18 mediates the rate of exocytosis by disassembling the exocyst higher-order structure after vesicle fusion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01374-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Human genetics guides the discovery of CARD9 inhibitors with anti-inflammatory activity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01426-6</link><description>A binder-first approach enables the identification of a druggable pocket and compound for the immune protein CARD9 that dampens its inflammatory signaling. This compound reduces cytokine production in immune cells and in a mouse model, demonstrating how therapeutic modulation can mimic effects of a CARD9 variant protective against Crohn’s disease.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01426-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Multimodal supramolecular targeting chimeras enable spatiotemporally resolved protein degradation in vivo</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01420-5</link><description>Supramolecular targeting chimeras (SupTACs) are a modular and programmable platform that enables tissue-specific and temporally controlled protein degradation in vivo across multiple animal species. SupTAC-mediated ACSL4 degradation effectively alleviates ferroptosis and pulmonary inflammation in a murine model of acute lung injury.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01420-5</guid></item><item><title>Science: A sudden change and recovery in the magnetic environment around a repeating fast radio
                     burst</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq3225</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq3225</guid></item><item><title>Science: Nucleotide metabolic rewiring enables NLRP3 inflammasome hyperactivation in obesity</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9006</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9006</guid></item><item><title>Science: Macrophage MR1 antigen presentation promotes MAIT cell immunity and lung microbiota
                     modulation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr6322</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr6322</guid></item><item><title>Science: Paleogeography modulates marine extinction risk throughout the Phanerozoic</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2627</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2627</guid></item><item><title>Science: Subventricular zone radial glial cells maintain inhibitory neuron production in the
                     human brain</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1803</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw1803</guid></item><item><title>Science: A hierarchical shell locks and stabilizes perovskite nanocrystals with near-unity
                     quantum yield</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady1370</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady1370</guid></item><item><title>Science: Complex mesoscale landscapes beneath Antarctica mapped from space</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2532</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2532</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of the lysosomal KICSTOR-GATOR1-SAMTOR nutrient-sensing supercomplex</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</link><description>This study reveals how KICSTOR and GATOR1 assemble into a crescent-shaped lysosomal complex that regulates mTORC1 during amino acid starvation and how SAMTOR binds KICSTOR in an S-adenosylmethionine-incompatible conformation to couple methionine sensing to mTORC1 regulation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: EcDNA-borne structural variants drive oncogenic fusion transcript amplification</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</link><description>Extrachromosomal DNA (ecDNA) is a major source of oncogenic fusions across cancer types, generating tissue-specific fusion landscapes with diagnostic potential. EcDNA-borne PVT1 5′-end fusions stabilize partner RNAs and boost oncogene output.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: In vivo detection of immune responses via cytokine activity labeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</link><description>Cytokine receptor dimerization, induced by the binding of cytokines, can be converted into a genetically traceable fluorescent signal and engineered into reporter mouse lines to visualize processes in vivo . An interleukin-17A reporter mouse line clarifies the location of IL-17A responsive cells in the ileum, while an interferon-γ line can highlight relevant effector populations of T cells in tumors.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Extracellular GPX4 impairs antitumor immunity via dendritic ZP3 receptors</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</link><description>GPX4 released by ferroptotic cancer cells suppresses dendritic cell maturation and T cell priming by binding to ZP3. Blocking the GPX4-ZP3 interaction restores dendritic activity, boosts cytotoxic T cells, and enhances chemo-, radio-, and immunotherapy efficacy in preclinical cancer models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A glycolytic shunt via the pentose phosphate pathway is a metabolic checkpoint for nervous system sensory homeostasis and axonal regeneration</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</link><description>The pentose phosphate pathway plays a dual role in enabling homeostatic and regenerative adaptations to environmental stimuli and injuries and can be leveraged to promote regeneration and recovery after spinal cord injury.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of pancreatic hIAPP fibrils derived from patients with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</link><description>Cryo-EM structures of hIAPP fibrils extracted from the surgically excised pancreases of patients with type 2 diabetes revealed a distinct fold with unique ligand binding compared to those prepared in vitro .</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: FOCAS: Transcriptome-wide screening of individual m 6 A sites functionally dissects epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</link><description>We developed FOCAS as a CRISPR-based platform enabling precise, high-throughput dissection of individual m 6 A sites across mRNA and carRNAs. It reveals RNA element-dependent m 6 A functions within genes, illuminating the context-dependent epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Neuronal calcium spikes enable vector inversion in the Drosophila brain</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</link><description>In the fly central complex, PFNa neurons switch from firing classical sodium spikes when depolarized to firing non-canonical T-type calcium spikes when hyperpolarized. This bidirectional spiking allows the PFNa population to signal both a standard two-dimensional vector and its inverse.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mapping cellular targets of covalent cancer drugs in the entire mammalian body</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</link><description>vCATCH is a volumetric tissue labeling technique enabling cellular-resolution mapping of covalent drug targets throughout the entire mammalian body.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nuclear speckle proteins form intrinsic and MALAT1 -dependent microphases</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</link><description>In nuclear speckles, sequence-encoded inter-domain attractive and repulsive interactions drive proteins to form hierarchical structures, including size-limited microphases, clusters of microphases, micron-scale double emulsions in protein mixtures, and microphases stabilized by preferential and protein-specific binding to the lncRNA MALAT1 .</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Targeting TFAP2β condensation suppresses the development of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</link><description>TFAP2β condensation suppresses esophageal squamous cell carcinoma progression by repressing ZNF131 transcription and recruiting other key regulators; the small molecule A6 enhances TFAP2β condensation and inhibits ESCC growth in cells, organoids, and mice, highlighting a potential therapeutic approach for ESCC.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Sensitized mast cells for targeted drug delivery and augmented cancer immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</link><description>IgE-sensitized mast cells loaded with anticancer drugs target antigen-positive tumors, releasing therapeutics as well as chemokines and cytokines for enhanced lymphocyte infiltration and improved local immunity, demonstrating potential for personalized cancer therapy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</guid></item></channel></rss>