<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Custom Biological Research Feed</title><link>https://mahoon2.github.io/custom_rss_feed/CNSfeed.xml</link><description>Aggregated research articles from Cell, Nature, and Science.</description><language>en-US</language><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Nature: Mosaic lateral heterostructures in two-dimensional perovskite</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09949-1</link><description>Colourful patterns in two-dimensional lead halide perovskites are created by letting them self-etch into tiny squares that can template epitaxial growth.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09949-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Dominant contribution of Asgard archaea to eukaryogenesis</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09960-6</link><description>A survey of the reconstructed gene set of the last eukaryotic common ancestor shows a consistent link between Asgard archaea and the origin of numerous, functionally diverse eukaryotic genes, demonstrating the dominant Asgard contribution to eukaryogenesis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09960-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Microbiota-induced T cell plasticity enables immune-mediated tumour control</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09913-z</link><description>Molecular mimicry between a gut commensal and a tumour antigen forms part of an important mechanistic framework that can boost the efficacy of immune checkpoint blockade therapy and restrain tumour growth.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09913-z</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Exciplex-enabled high-efficiency, fully stretchable OLEDs</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09904-0</link><description>Fabrication of fully stretchable organic light-emitting diodes incorporating an intrinsically stretchable exciplex-assisted phosphorescent layer along with MXene-contact stretchable electrodes is described, demonstrating high efficiency and mechanical compliance for applications in next-generation wearable and deformable displays.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09904-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Direct observation of the Migdal effect induced by neutron bombardment</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09918-8</link><description>Direct observation of the Migdal effect in neutron–nucleus collisions is reported, which resolves a long-standing gap in experimental validation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09918-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Training large language models on narrow tasks can lead to broad misalignment</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09937-5</link><description>Finetuning a large language model on a narrow task of writing insecure code causes a broad range of concerning behaviours unrelated to coding.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09937-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Coherent nonlinear X-ray four-photon interaction with core-shell electrons</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09911-1</link><description>Using single broadband X-ray pulses from a free-electron laser on a gaseous neon target, coherent, nonlinear four-photon interactions with core–shell electrons is demonstrated, representing a strategy for multidimensional correlation spectroscopy at the atomic scale.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09911-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: A foundation model for continuous glucose monitoring data</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09925-9</link><description>GluFormer, a generative foundation model, uses continuous glucose monitoring data to accurately forecast glycaemia-related health responses, particularly for long-term outcomes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09925-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: 3D-printed low-voltage-driven ciliary hydrogel microactuators</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09944-6</link><description>3D-printed gel microcilia arrays printed by two-photon polymerization and composed of a soft acrylic acid-co-acrylamide hydrogel with a nanometre-scale network structure are shown to respond to low-voltage electrical stimuli within milliseconds, enabling dynamic individual control and non-reciprocal 3D motion.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09944-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Ligand-specific activation trajectories dictate GPCR signalling in cells</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09963-3</link><description>Different agonists produce equilibria of at least four distinct active states of the G-protein-bound M2 muscarinic acetylcholine receptor, each with a different ability to activate G proteins.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09963-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Disease tolerance and infection pathogenesis age-related tradeoffs in mice</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09923-x</link><description>Disease course and pathology an infection may cause can change owing to the structural and functional physiological changes that accumulate with age, but therapy can be tailored accordingly; disease tolerance genes show antagonistic pleiotropy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09923-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Global subsidence of river deltas</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09928-6</link><description>Spatially variable surface-elevation changes across 40 global deltas using interferometric synthetic aperture radar are reported.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09928-6</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Trapping of single atoms in metasurface optical tweezer arrays</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09961-5</link><description>Single strontium atoms are trapped in optical tweezer arrays generated via holographic metasurfaces, overcoming a critical barrier to realizing scalable neutral-atom quantum technologies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09961-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: A nowhere-to-hide mechanism ensures complete piRNA-directed DNA methylation</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09940-w</link><description>In mice, a SPOCD1–TPR-dependent ‘nowhere-to-hide’ mechanism is required for complete non-stochastic piRNA-directed LINE1 DNA methylation by preventing transposons from escaping surveillance within heterochromatin.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09940-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: The ubiquitin ligase KLHL6 drives resistance to CD8 + T cell dysfunction</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09926-8</link><description>Integrating computational analyses of T cell exhaustion and mitochondrial fitness atlases with in vivo CRISPR screens has identified KLHL6 as a dual-negative regulator of both exhaustion differentiation and mitochondrial dysfunction, highlighting its potential as a target to enhance anti-tumour immunity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09926-8</guid></item><item><title>Nature: N 1 -Methylpseudouridine directly modulates translation dynamics</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09945-5</link><description>N 1 -Methylpseudouridine enhances the translation of synthetic mRNAs, independently of innate immunity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09945-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Little red dots as young supermassive black holes in dense ionized cocoons</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09900-4</link><description>The highest-quality JWST spectra reveal that little red dots are young supermassive black holes shrouded in dense cocoons of ionized gas, where electron scattering, not Doppler motions, broadens their spectral lines.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09900-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Ultra-high-throughput mapping of genetic design space</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09933-9</link><description>CLASSIC is a high-throughput genetic profiling platform that combines long- and short-read next-generation-sequencing modalities to quantitatively assess pools of constructs of arbitrary length containing diverse genetic part compositions.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09933-9</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Language model-guided anticipation and discovery of mammalian metabolites</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09969-x</link><description>Chemical language models trained on known metabolites can identify previously unknown metabolites from mass spectrometry-based metabolomics data with high accuracy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09969-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: CFAP20 salvages arrested RNAPII from the path of co-directional replisomes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09943-7</link><description>CFAP20 has a key role in rescuing RNA polymerase II complexes that have arrested during DNA transcription, limiting the accumulation of R-loops and preventing collisions between the transcription and replication machinery.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09943-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Myelin antigen capture in the CNS by B cells expressing EBV latent membrane protein 1 leads to demyelinating lesion formation</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01480-1</link><description>Myelin-reactive B cells entering the central nervous system capture cognate antigen from the parenchyma. Without T cell help, they rapidly die; however, Epstein-Barr virus LMP1 enables them to bypass this checkpoint and cause demyelination, as seen in multiple sclerosis.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01480-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: EBV infection and HLA-DR15 jointly drive multiple sclerosis by myelin peptide presentation</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01495-3</link><description>EBV infection alters the transcriptome of B cells, which leads to presentation of MBP peptides on HLA-DR15 molecules. MBP peptide-specific CD4 + T cells are found in the peripheral immune compartment and CNS, where they recognize the same MBP peptides on HLA-DR15 molecules.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01495-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Anoctamin-2-specific T cells link Epstein-Barr virus to multiple sclerosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01481-3</link><description>Researchers identified anoctamin-2 (ANO2) as a frequent autoimmune target in multiple sclerosis, with T cell responses against ANO2 occurring in over half of patients. These ANO2-specific T cells share cross-reactivity and pathogenic features with T cell responses to EBNA1 from Epstein-Barr virus, and their activation worsens MS-like disease in mice.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01481-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of the lysosomal KICSTOR-GATOR1-SAMTOR nutrient-sensing supercomplex</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</link><description>This study reveals how KICSTOR and GATOR1 assemble into a crescent-shaped lysosomal complex that regulates mTORC1 during amino acid starvation and how SAMTOR binds KICSTOR in an S-adenosylmethionine-incompatible conformation to couple methionine sensing to mTORC1 regulation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01418-7</guid></item><item><title>Science: A precessing jet from an active galactic nucleus drives gas outflow from a disk galaxy</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adp8989</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adp8989</guid></item><item><title>Science: Dogs with a large vocabulary of object labels learn new labels by overhearing like
                     1.5-year-old infants</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq5474</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq5474</guid></item><item><title>Science: Self-induced Floquet magnons in magnetic vortices</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9891</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq9891</guid></item><item><title>Science: Mapping somatosensory afferent circuitry to bone identifies neurotrophic signals required
                     for fracture healing</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr9608</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr9608</guid></item><item><title>Science: Deep contrastive learning enables genome-wide virtual screening</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads9530</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads9530</guid></item><item><title>Science: IDH-mutant gliomas arise from glial progenitor cells harboring the initial driver
                     mutation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt0559</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt0559</guid></item><item><title>Science: Chinese Immune Multi-Omics Atlas</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt3130</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt3130</guid></item><item><title>Science: Bark microbiota modulate climate-active gas fluxes in Australian forests</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2182</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu2182</guid></item><item><title>Science: Computational design of conformation-biasing mutations to alter protein functions</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv7953</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv7953</guid></item><item><title>Science: Leveraging triatropic rearrangements for stereoselective skeletal reshuffling</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3340</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw3340</guid></item><item><title>Science: Ontogeny of the spinal cord dorsal horn</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5781</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx5781</guid></item><item><title>Science: Mitochondrial control of fuel switching via carnitine biosynthesis</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady5532</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady5532</guid></item><item><title>Science: Multivalent ligands regulate dimensional engineering for inverted perovskite solar
                     modules</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea0656</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea0656</guid></item><item><title>Science: Facial gestures are enacted through a cortical hierarchy of dynamic and stable codes</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea0890</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea0890</guid></item><item><title>Science: Molecular press annealing enables robust perovskite solar cells</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea8228</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea8228</guid></item><item><title>Science: The molecular basis of the binding and specific activation of rhizobial NodD by flavonoids</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec3061</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec3061</guid></item><item><title>Science: Access to four-membered cyclic sulfinamides by energy transfer catalysis</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec3158</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec3158</guid></item><item><title>Cell: EcDNA-borne structural variants drive oncogenic fusion transcript amplification</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</link><description>Extrachromosomal DNA (ecDNA) is a major source of oncogenic fusions across cancer types, generating tissue-specific fusion landscapes with diagnostic potential. EcDNA-borne PVT1 5′-end fusions stabilize partner RNAs and boost oncogene output.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01422-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: In vivo detection of immune responses via cytokine activity labeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</link><description>Cytokine receptor dimerization, induced by the binding of cytokines, can be converted into a genetically traceable fluorescent signal and engineered into reporter mouse lines to visualize processes in vivo . An interleukin-17A reporter mouse line clarifies the location of IL-17A responsive cells in the ileum, while an interferon-γ line can highlight relevant effector populations of T cells in tumors.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01424-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Evolutionary transcriptomics unveils rapid changes of gene expression patterns in flowering plants</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01428-X</link><description>Evolutionary transcriptome analysis of seven angiosperm (flowering plant) species uncovers rapid evolution of gene expression patterns, particularly for genes involved in the responses to endogenous and environmental stimuli. A comparative analysis with available data from mammals confirms different rates of expression divergence in both clades and kingdoms.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01428-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Extracellular GPX4 impairs antitumor immunity via dendritic ZP3 receptors</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</link><description>GPX4 released by ferroptotic cancer cells suppresses dendritic cell maturation and T cell priming by binding to ZP3. Blocking the GPX4-ZP3 interaction restores dendritic activity, boosts cytotoxic T cells, and enhances chemo-, radio-, and immunotherapy efficacy in preclinical cancer models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01378-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A glycolytic shunt via the pentose phosphate pathway is a metabolic checkpoint for nervous system sensory homeostasis and axonal regeneration</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</link><description>The pentose phosphate pathway plays a dual role in enabling homeostatic and regenerative adaptations to environmental stimuli and injuries and can be leveraged to promote regeneration and recovery after spinal cord injury.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01379-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structure of pancreatic hIAPP fibrils derived from patients with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</link><description>Cryo-EM structures of hIAPP fibrils extracted from the surgically excised pancreases of patients with type 2 diabetes revealed a distinct fold with unique ligand binding compared to those prepared in vitro .</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01377-7</guid></item><item><title>Science: Giant enhancement of exciton diffusion near an electronic Mott insulator</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads5266</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ads5266</guid></item><item><title>Science: Genomic and morphometric evidence for Austronesian-mediated pig translocation in the
                     Pacific</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv4963</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv4963</guid></item><item><title>Science: SPARK-seq: A high-throughput platform for aptamer discovery and kinetic profiling</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv6127</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv6127</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Butyrolactol A enhances caspofungin efficacy via flippase inhibition in drug-resistant fungi</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01371-6</link><description>Chen et al. identify the natural product butyrolactol A as an inhibitor of the phospholipid flippase Apt1-Cdc50, which it locks in a nonfunctional state. By disrupting membrane homeostasis and enhancing drug uptake, butyrolactol A restores echinocandin efficacy against intrinsically resistant fungal pathogens, including Cryptococcus and Candida auris.</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01371-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: FOCAS: Transcriptome-wide screening of individual m 6 A sites functionally dissects epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</link><description>We developed FOCAS as a CRISPR-based platform enabling precise, high-throughput dissection of individual m 6 A sites across mRNA and carRNAs. It reveals RNA element-dependent m 6 A functions within genes, illuminating the context-dependent epitranscriptomic control of gene expression in cancer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01372-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mechanisms of HSV-1 helicase-primase inhibition and replication fork complex assembly</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01376-5</link><description>Cryo-EM structures of HSV-1 helicase-primase and replication fork complexes reveal mechanisms of drug inhibition, features that explain drug selectivity, and the molecular basis of replication fork complex assembly during herpesvirus DNA replication.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01376-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Neuronal calcium spikes enable vector inversion in the Drosophila brain</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</link><description>In the fly central complex, PFNa neurons switch from firing classical sodium spikes when depolarized to firing non-canonical T-type calcium spikes when hyperpolarized. This bidirectional spiking allows the PFNa population to signal both a standard two-dimensional vector and its inverse.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01375-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Tumor-produced ammonia is metabolized by regulatory T cells to further impede anti-tumor immunity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01369-8</link><description>Tumor metabolism selectively enriches Tregs to achieve immunosuppression, but the underlying mechanisms remain unclear. Here, we show that tumor-derived ammonia drives Treg-specific enrichment. Tregs detoxify ammonia via the urea cycle and spermine synthesis, which enhances their function, revealing how Tregs adapt in tumors and suggesting strategies for next-generation cancer immunotherapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01369-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Hepatic adaptation to chronic metabolic stress primes tumorigenesis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01366-2</link><description>Environmental stresses, such as a high-fat diet, disrupt liver cell balance by promoting pro-survival, developmental, and regenerative programs while impairing key tissue functions. These stress responses—driven by metabolism, transcription factors, and intercellular signaling—increase cancer risk months to years in the future.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01366-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mapping cellular targets of covalent cancer drugs in the entire mammalian body</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</link><description>vCATCH is a volumetric tissue labeling technique enabling cellular-resolution mapping of covalent drug targets throughout the entire mammalian body.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nuclear speckle proteins form intrinsic and MALAT1 -dependent microphases</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</link><description>In nuclear speckles, sequence-encoded inter-domain attractive and repulsive interactions drive proteins to form hierarchical structures, including size-limited microphases, clusters of microphases, micron-scale double emulsions in protein mixtures, and microphases stabilized by preferential and protein-specific binding to the lncRNA MALAT1 .</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Dendritic cells regulate the innate-adaptive balance in lymph nodes for optimal host defense</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01362-5</link><description>Dendritic cells in lymph nodes orchestrate large-scale innate effector cell trafficking to contain pathogens, but this disrupts tissue structure and early adaptive immunity. After pathogen control, dendritic cells and recruited monocytes restore lymph node architecture to allow potent adaptive responses to ensue, collectively enabling both immediate and long-term host defense.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01362-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Intravital observation of neuronal and immune cell dynamics in the developing mammalian brain</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01313-3</link><description>The establishment of the intravital imaging of externally immobilized embryos (IMEE) method enables stable, high-resolution imaging of mouse embryos to investigate cellular dynamics in the developing mouse brain, including neuronal migration patterns, neurons’ dynamic interactions with vasculature and microglia, and microglial surveillance behaviors under physiological conditions and environmental stress.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01313-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Targeting TFAP2β condensation suppresses the development of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</link><description>TFAP2β condensation suppresses esophageal squamous cell carcinoma progression by repressing ZNF131 transcription and recruiting other key regulators; the small molecule A6 enhances TFAP2β condensation and inhibits ESCC growth in cells, organoids, and mice, highlighting a potential therapeutic approach for ESCC.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Multimodal AI generates virtual population for tumor microenvironment modeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</link><description>GigaTIME leverages multimodal AI to generate virtual multiplex immunofluorescence (mIF) profiles from standard H&amp;E slides, enabling comprehensive tumor immune microenvironment modeling across a large (&gt;14,000) and diverse patient population. This virtual approach unlocks new opportunities for large-scale clinical discoveries that were previously hindered by the scarcity of mIF data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Sensitized mast cells for targeted drug delivery and augmented cancer immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</link><description>IgE-sensitized mast cells loaded with anticancer drugs target antigen-positive tumors, releasing therapeutics as well as chemokines and cytokines for enhanced lymphocyte infiltration and improved local immunity, demonstrating potential for personalized cancer therapy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structural basis of microtubule-mediated signal transduction</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</link><description>This study presents a structural basis for understanding how microtubules can act as spatiotemporal signal sensors to control cellular responses.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Psilocybin triggers an activity-dependent rewiring of large-scale cortical networks</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</link><description>Psilocybin reshapes brain networks through activity-dependent plasticity, including a weakening of recurrent cortical loops that could underlie its therapeutic effects.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: pTα enhances mRNA translation and potentiates CAR T cells for solid tumor eradication</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</link><description>Addition of a pre-TCR domain to chimeric antigen receptors boosts mRNA translation and enables durable tumor control by T cells in both blood and solid cancers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: The unique architecture of umbrella toxins permits a two-tiered molecular bet-hedging strategy for interbacterial antagonism</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</link><description>Umbrella toxin particles produced by Actinobacteria contain five spokes tipped with variable lectin domains. Here, Zhao et al. show that these lectins mediate species-specific binding to a previously unrecognized cell surface carbohydrate polymer and propose that the modular nature of umbrella particles enables bet hedging against unpredictable competitor encounters.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Elucidating pathway-selective biased CCKBR agonism for Alzheimer’s disease treatment</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</link><description>Clinical evidence from AD patients reveals an association between impaired CCKBR-Gq signaling and disease severity, guiding structure-based design of a Gq-biased agonist that rescues memory and pathology in AD animal models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: BRAIN-MAGNET: A functional genomics atlas for interpretation of non-coding variants</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</link><description>BRAIN-MAGNET, a convolutional neural network trained on 148,198 functionally tested non-coding regulatory elements, predicts enhancer activity directly from DNA sequence and identifies nucleotides essential for function. This functional genomic atlas and BRAIN-MAGNET prioritize disease-relevant non-coding variants, advancing functional interpretation of the regulatory genome in neurodevelopment and neurological disease.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</guid></item></channel></rss>