<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Custom Biological Research Feed</title><link>https://mahoon2.github.io/custom_rss_feed/CNSfeed.xml</link><description>Aggregated research articles from Cell, Nature, and Science.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Cell: Tumor-produced ammonia is metabolized by regulatory T cells to further impede anti-tumor immunity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01369-8</link><description>Tumor metabolism selectively enriches Tregs to achieve immunosuppression, but the underlying mechanisms remain unclear. Here, we show that tumor-derived ammonia drives Treg-specific enrichment. Tregs detoxify ammonia via the urea cycle and spermine synthesis, which enhances their function, revealing how Tregs adapt in tumors and suggesting strategies for next-generation cancer immunotherapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01369-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Modeling human embryo implantation in vitro</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01232-2</link><description>Building an in vitro model of receptive endometrium allows investigation of human embryo implantation and early post-implantation development and recapitulates the earliest stages in establishing the human placenta and formation of the embryo-endometrial interface.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01232-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A 3D in vitro model for studying human implantation and implantation failure</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01230-9</link><description>A 3D in-chip implantation model is developed using a bioengineered human endometrioid and human blastoids or blastocysts and used to identify candidate compounds that can enhance implantation rates in endometrioids derived from patients experiencing recurrent implantation failure.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01230-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Hepatic adaptation to chronic metabolic stress primes tumorigenesis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01366-2</link><description>Environmental stresses, such as a high-fat diet, disrupt liver cell balance by promoting pro-survival, developmental, and regenerative programs while impairing key tissue functions. These stress responses—driven by metabolism, transcription factors, and intercellular signaling—increase cancer risk months to years in the future.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01366-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Mapping cellular targets of covalent cancer drugs in the entire mammalian body</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</link><description>vCATCH is a volumetric tissue labeling technique enabling cellular-resolution mapping of covalent drug targets throughout the entire mammalian body.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01365-0</guid></item><item><title>Nature: NAC controls nascent chain fate through tunnel sensing and chaperone action</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10058-2</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10058-2</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Non-equilibrium snapshots of ligand efficacy at the μ-opioid receptor</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10056-4</link><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10056-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Nuclear speckle proteins form intrinsic and MALAT1 -dependent microphases</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</link><description>In nuclear speckles, sequence-encoded inter-domain attractive and repulsive interactions drive proteins to form hierarchical structures, including size-limited microphases, clusters of microphases, micron-scale double emulsions in protein mixtures, and microphases stabilized by preferential and protein-specific binding to the lncRNA MALAT1 .</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01361-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Dendritic cells regulate the innate-adaptive balance in lymph nodes for optimal host defense</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01362-5</link><description>Dendritic cells in lymph nodes orchestrate large-scale innate effector cell trafficking to contain pathogens, but this disrupts tissue structure and early adaptive immunity. After pathogen control, dendritic cells and recruited monocytes restore lymph node architecture to allow potent adaptive responses to ensue, collectively enabling both immediate and long-term host defense.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01362-5</guid></item><item><title>Science: State-independent ionic conductivity</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adk0786</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adk0786</guid></item><item><title>Science: Risks of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substance exposure through marine fish consumption</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr0351</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr0351</guid></item><item><title>Science: AQP5: A functional gastric cancer stem cell marker in mouse and human tumors</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr2428</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adr2428</guid></item><item><title>Science: Extending the temperature range of the Cmcm phase of SnSe for high thermoelectric performance</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt0831</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt0831</guid></item><item><title>Science: A second planetesimal collision in the Fomalhaut system</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu6266</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu6266</guid></item><item><title>Science: Ancient genomes illuminate the origins and dynamic history of East Asian cattle</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu9904</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adu9904</guid></item><item><title>Science: Chromatin buffers torsional stress during transcription</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv0134</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv0134</guid></item><item><title>Science: All-optical synthesis chip for large-scale intelligent semantic vision generation</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv7434</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv7434</guid></item><item><title>Science: Conformational landscape adaptations enable processive phosphorylation by Src family
                     kinases</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8310</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adw8310</guid></item><item><title>Science: Intracellular competition shapes plasmid population dynamics</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx0665</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx0665</guid></item><item><title>Science: A human pan-disease blood atlas of the circulating proteome</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2678</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adx2678</guid></item><item><title>Science: Extreme plate boundary localization promotes shallow earthquake slip at the Japan
                     Trench</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady0234</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady0234</guid></item><item><title>Science: Trifluoromethylation of alkyl electrophiles with 11 C- or 18 F-labeled fluoroform for PET applications</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2969</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady2969</guid></item><item><title>Science: Multistep genomics on single cells and live cultures in subnanoliter capsules</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady7209</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady7209</guid></item><item><title>Science: High-throughput single cell omics using semipermeable capsules</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady7227</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady7227</guid></item><item><title>Science: A bacterial nutrition strategy for plant disease control</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady8325</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.ady8325</guid></item><item><title>Science: A cellular basis for heightened gut sensitivity in females</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz1398</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz1398</guid></item><item><title>Science: Optimal perovskite vapor partitioning on textured silicon for high-stability tandem
                     solar cells</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz3698</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz3698</guid></item><item><title>Science: Xanthomonas coordinates type III–type II effector synergy by activating fruit-ripening pathway</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9239</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adz9239</guid></item><item><title>Science: Electrode strain dynamics in layered intercalation battery cathodes</title><link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea2763</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aea2763</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Gut microbiota promotes immune tolerance at the maternal-fetal interface</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01318-2</link><description>Microbiota-dependent tryptophan-derived indole deficiency is linked to mouse fetal resorption and human recurrent miscarriage. Tryptophan-derived indoles prime MDSCs and RORγt+ Tregs to suppress IFN-γ+ or IL-17A+ T cells at the maternal-fetal interface, respectively, thereby promoting maternal-fetal immune tolerance.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01318-2</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Mazdutide versus dulaglutide in Chinese adults with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10031-z</link><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10031-z</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Mazdutide versus placebo in Chinese adults with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10026-w</link><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-10026-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Transient hepatic reconstitution of trophic factors enhances aged immunity</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09873-4</link><description>Using lipid nanoparticle delivery of mRNAs to the liver in aged mice, T cell function and declining immune cues can be restored.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09873-4</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Gene-specific selective sweeps are pervasive across human gut microbiomes</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09798-y</link><description>Development and application of the integrated linkage disequilibrium score (iLDS) reveals both selective pressures impacting the human gut microbiome and the mechanisms by which gut bacteria adapt to meet them.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09798-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: GTP release-selective agonists prolong opioid analgesic efficacy</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09880-5</link><description>Mu opioid receptor agonists with a preference for the non-GTP-bound state of the G protein promote GTP release, thereby potentiating antinociceptive effects of drugs such as morphine and fentanyl without also increasing their respiratory or cardiac effects.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09880-5</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Programmable 200 GOPS Hopfield-inspired photonic Ising machine</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09838-7</link><description>An architecture inspired by Hopfield networks based on a programmable, stable, room-temperature optoelectronic oscillator-based photonics Ising machine is introduced that can be used to efficiently address optimization and combinatorics problems.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09838-7</guid></item><item><title>Nature: An integrated view of the structure and function of the human 4D nucleome</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09890-3</link><description>The 4D Nucleome Project demonstrates the use of genomic assays and computational methods to measure genome folding and then predict genomic structure from DNA sequence, facilitating the discovery of potential effects of genetic variants, including variants associated with disease, on genome structure and function.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09890-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Palaeometabolomes yield biological and ecological profiles at early human sites</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09843-w</link><description>Metabolic and proteomic profiles derived from fossilized skeletal remains of animals enable inferences regarding physiological health and disease as well as diet to provide reconstructions of ancient soil, vegetation and palaeoclimate characteristics.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09843-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Astrocyte CCN1 stabilizes neural circuits in the adult brain</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09770-w</link><description>Neural circuits in adult mouse visual cortex are stabilized by astrocytes, which secrete CCN1, resulting in reduced plasticity and increased maturation of multiple cell types.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09770-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: An 11-qubit atom processor in silicon</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09827-w</link><description>An 11-qubit atom processor comprising two precision-placed nuclear spin registers of phosphorus in silicon is shown to achieve state-of-the-art Bell-state fidelities of up to 99.5%.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09827-w</guid></item><item><title>Nature: The global hydrogen budget</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09806-1</link><description>Trends in global H 2 sources and sinks are analysed from 1990 to 2020, and a comprehensive budget for the decade 2010–2020 is presented.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09806-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Visualizing interaction-driven restructuring of quantum Hall edge states</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09858-3</link><description>Scanning tunnelling microscopy is used to image pristine electrostatically defined quantum Hall edge states in graphene with high spatial resolution and demonstrate their interaction-driven restructuring.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09858-3</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Prevalence of Alzheimer’s disease pathology in the community</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09841-y</link><description>The prevalence of Alzheimer’s disease neuropathological changes is reported based on blood-based biomarkers in a Norwegian population-based cohort.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09841-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Titan’s strong tidal dissipation precludes a subsurface ocean</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09818-x</link><description>Reanalysis of radiometric data from Cassini indicates that Titan does not contain a subsurface ocean, as strong tidal dissipation observed in its gravity field is not consistent with the presence of a liquid layer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09818-x</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Human assembloids recapitulate periportal liver tissue in vitro</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09884-1</link><description>Hepatocyte organoids derived directly from human tissue enable long-term hepatocyte expansion and can be combined with portal mesenchyme and cholangiocyte organoids to form a donor-specific periportal liver assembloid system.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09884-1</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Spatiotemporal cellular map of the developing human reproductive tract</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09875-2</link><description>A detailed spatiotemporal roadmap of the human female and male reproductive tracts during key periods of sexual differentiation provides new cellular and molecular insights into how early axial gradients lead to specific cell lineages and tissue structures.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09875-2</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Lesion-remote astrocytes govern microglia-mediated white matter repair</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09887-y</link><description>After spinal cord injury, lesion-remote astrocytes acquire heterogeneous, spatially restricted reactivity states that shape neuroinflammation, neural repair and neurological recovery.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09887-y</guid></item><item><title>Nature: Laser spectroscopy and CP-violation sensitivity of actinium monofluoride</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09814-1</link><description>Gas-phase actinium monofluoride (AcF) has been produced and spectroscopically studied at the CERN-ISOLDE radioactive ion beam facility; the results highlight the potential of 227 AcF for exceptionally sensitive searches of CP violation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09814-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Intravital observation of neuronal and immune cell dynamics in the developing mammalian brain</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01313-3</link><description>The establishment of the intravital imaging of externally immobilized embryos (IMEE) method enables stable, high-resolution imaging of mouse embryos to investigate cellular dynamics in the developing mouse brain, including neuronal migration patterns, neurons’ dynamic interactions with vasculature and microglia, and microglial surveillance behaviors under physiological conditions and environmental stress.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01313-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Targeting TFAP2β condensation suppresses the development of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</link><description>TFAP2β condensation suppresses esophageal squamous cell carcinoma progression by repressing ZNF131 transcription and recruiting other key regulators; the small molecule A6 enhances TFAP2β condensation and inhibits ESCC growth in cells, organoids, and mice, highlighting a potential therapeutic approach for ESCC.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01315-7</guid></item><item><title>Cell: HLA export by melanoma cells decoys cytotoxic T cells to promote immune evasion</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01316-9</link><description>Melanoma cells escape immune surveillance by releasing MHC-antigen-loaded large EVs, known as melanosomes, that directly engage and impair CD8 + T cell receptors.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01316-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Multimodal AI generates virtual population for tumor microenvironment modeling</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</link><description>GigaTIME leverages multimodal AI to generate virtual multiplex immunofluorescence (mIF) profiles from standard H&amp;E slides, enabling comprehensive tumor immune microenvironment modeling across a large (&gt;14,000) and diverse patient population. This virtual approach unlocks new opportunities for large-scale clinical discoveries that were previously hindered by the scarcity of mIF data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01312-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Sensitized mast cells for targeted drug delivery and augmented cancer immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</link><description>IgE-sensitized mast cells loaded with anticancer drugs target antigen-positive tumors, releasing therapeutics as well as chemokines and cytokines for enhanced lymphocyte infiltration and improved local immunity, demonstrating potential for personalized cancer therapy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01311-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Biomaterial-minimalistic photoactivated bioprinting of cell-dense tissues</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01308-X</link><description>We developed a bioprinting strategy that turns living cells into cell-only bioinks, enabling light-based 3D bioprinting of tissues at native, ultrahigh cell densities (up to ∼10 9 cells mL −1 ) to rapidly yield functional neural circuit and beating mini-heart models as well as vascularized liver and skin grafts that promote regeneration.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01308-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Structural basis of microtubule-mediated signal transduction</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</link><description>This study presents a structural basis for understanding how microtubules can act as spatiotemporal signal sensors to control cellular responses.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01307-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Psilocybin triggers an activity-dependent rewiring of large-scale cortical networks</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</link><description>Psilocybin reshapes brain networks through activity-dependent plasticity, including a weakening of recurrent cortical loops that could underlie its therapeutic effects.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01305-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: A fin-loop-like structure in GPX4 underlies neuroprotection from ferroptosis</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01310-8</link><description>A fin-like structural loop in GPX4 is critical for anchoring the enzyme to cellular membranes, thereby preventing ferroptosis. A patient-associated R152H mutation destabilizes this loop, leading to ferroptotic neurodegeneration in human cells and mouse models and revealing Alzheimer’s-like molecular signatures. These findings position ferroptosis as a critical driver (and potential therapeutic target) of neurodegenerative disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01310-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Renal PIEZO2 is an essential regulator of renin</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01309-1</link><description>The force-sensing ion channel PIEZO2 is an essential regulator of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS), a pathway that controls blood volume. Loss of PIEZO2 in the kidney cells that produce renin disrupts cellular calcium dynamics and levels of the enzyme in mice, linking mechanotransduction in the kidney to the RAAS.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01309-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Autoantibody-triggered podocyte membrane budding drives autoimmune kidney disease</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01306-6</link><description>Kidney podocytes of the blood-urine filter form autoimmunoglobulin-triggered extracellular vesicles (AIT-EVs) for intra- and extracellular waste removal into the urine, a cellular reaction that links basal immune complex clearance to podocyte injury and allows non-invasive diagnosis and monitoring of kidney autoimmune activity.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01306-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: pTα enhances mRNA translation and potentiates CAR T cells for solid tumor eradication</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</link><description>Addition of a pre-TCR domain to chimeric antigen receptors boosts mRNA translation and enables durable tumor control by T cells in both blood and solid cancers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01254-1</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Membrane potential mediates the cellular response to mechanical pressure</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01253-X</link><description>Cells in tissues need to know when to start growing and when to stop growing to quickly heal wounds but prevent tumorous overgrowth. Membrane potential allows cells to sense physical forces, including those from neighboring cells, and thereby regulates growth.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01253-X</guid></item><item><title>Cell: The unique architecture of umbrella toxins permits a two-tiered molecular bet-hedging strategy for interbacterial antagonism</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</link><description>Umbrella toxin particles produced by Actinobacteria contain five spokes tipped with variable lectin domains. Here, Zhao et al. show that these lectins mediate species-specific binding to a previously unrecognized cell surface carbohydrate polymer and propose that the modular nature of umbrella particles enables bet hedging against unpredictable competitor encounters.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01249-8</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Thermodynamic principles link in vitro transcription factor affinities to single-molecule chromatin states in cells</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01300-5</link><description>In vitro -derived insights into features that drive transcription factor binding to DNA, including motif-adjacent sequence, enable prediction of chromatin states and transcription factor occupancy in cells.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01300-5</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Stress-induced sympathetic hyperactivation drives hair follicle necrosis to trigger autoimmunity</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01247-4</link><description>Acute stress causes immediate hair follicle necrosis and hair loss via sympathetic nerves, which in turn activates and expands autoreactive CD8⁺ T cells targeting hair follicles. Thus, a single stress event not only causes immediate tissue damage but also predisposes the tissue to future autoimmune attack.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01247-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: IL-1R1-positive dorsal raphe neurons drive self-imposed social withdrawal in sickness</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01245-0</link><description>During sickness, animals exhibit prolonged social withdrawal, a response that may limit disease spread. Elevated IL-1β levels during inflammation activate IL-1R1-expressing neurons in the dorsal raphe nucleus to drive self-imposed withdrawal, highlighting a neural mechanism through which immune activation reconfigures social behavior.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01245-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: RNA innate immunity constitutes a barrier for interspecies chimerism</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01244-9</link><description>Interspecies PSC co-culture induces horizontal RNA transfer that activates innate immunity in “winner” mouse cells, a response that is alleviated by Mavs deletion, thereby enhancing “loser” human PSC survival and chimerism.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01244-9</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Elucidating pathway-selective biased CCKBR agonism for Alzheimer’s disease treatment</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</link><description>Clinical evidence from AD patients reveals an association between impaired CCKBR-Gq signaling and disease severity, guiding structure-based design of a Gq-biased agonist that rescues memory and pathology in AD animal models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01238-3</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Inhibition of heme biosynthesis triggers cuproptosis in acute myeloid leukemia</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01233-4</link><description>Reduced levels of the essential metabolite heme are a common feature of acute myeloid leukemia, and consequently, leukemic cells are highly sensitive to inhibition of de novo heme synthesis. Blockade of heme biosynthesis enzymes triggers cuproptosis, a form of copper-dependent cell death that is molecularly distinct from other cell death pathways.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01233-4</guid></item><item><title>Cell: BRAIN-MAGNET: A functional genomics atlas for interpretation of non-coding variants</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</link><description>BRAIN-MAGNET, a convolutional neural network trained on 148,198 functionally tested non-coding regulatory elements, predicts enhancer activity directly from DNA sequence and identifies nucleotides essential for function. This functional genomic atlas and BRAIN-MAGNET prioritize disease-relevant non-coding variants, advancing functional interpretation of the regulatory genome in neurodevelopment and neurological disease.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01234-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Ancient RNA expression profiles from the extinct woolly mammoth</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01231-0</link><description>Ancient RNA profiles from Late Pleistocene woolly mammoths were sequenced from permafrost-preserved mummified tissues, revealing tissue-specific transcriptional functions and gene expression regulatory dynamics. These findings highlight the potential of ancient RNA molecules to provide additional biological information, thus advancing toward integrative paleogenetic research beyond the limits of DNA sequencing alone.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01231-0</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Single-cell susceptibility to viral infection is driven by variable cell states</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01193-6</link><description>Not all cells that can be infected by a virus become infected with that virus. Single-cell clone tracing reveals intrinsic cell states with variable expression patterns that increase susceptibility to viral infection, and this applies for several distinct viruses.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01193-6</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Molecular grammars of predicted intrinsically disordered regions that span the human proteome</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01191-2</link><description>Grammars inferred using NARDINI+ (GIN) is a resource that uncovers molecular grammars of intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs) across the human proteome, revealing how distinct grammars underlie protein localization, function, and disease associations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01191-2</guid></item><item><title>Cell: Genome sequences of extant and extinct gibbons reveal their phylogeny, demographic history, and conservation status</title><link>https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01181-X</link><description>This study presents a comprehensive evolutionary history of gibbons by resolving their contentious phylogeny, reclassifying an extinct species with ancient DNA, and identifying a structural variant potentially contributing to their limb elongation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(25)01181-X</guid></item></channel></rss>